Elizabeth Glenn, PhD

Email: elizabeth.guy86@gmail.com Phone: 425-829-5627

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elizabeth-glenn-phd/

Sr. Data Scientist with 6 years of industry experience combined with 6 years of academic research experience and 3 years of technical sales, marketing, and product management experience. Particular expertise in building out Experimentation platforms from the ground up for incremental analyses. Avid mountain ultra trail runner.

Skills:

Statistics and Machine Learning: Econometrics, Bayesian and Frequentist A/B testing, Complex Linear and Logistic Regression, Causal Impact Modeling, ANOVA Statistical Software and Programming: Python (Pandas, PyMC3), SQL, PySpark, R (beginner), Scala (beginner), ETL pipeline management (Databricks and Azkaban) Visualization: Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tableau, Periscope

Experience:

Sr. Data Scientist - Starbucks Coffee Company (Oct 2022-Present):.

- Developed measurement strategy, evaluation metrics, and reporting for the first AB tests in the international business for Starbucks Rewards program.
- Utilized causal inference methodology to build out counterfactual scenarios for international store testing.
- Created initial code base and strategic framework for standardized customer behavior tables from raw data feeds.

Sr. Decision Scientist - Experimentation and Data Platform - Remitly (Oct 2021-Oct 2022):

- Built and led strategy on the centralized experimentation platform, including ETL pipeline development and statistical methodology. Led A/B testing "Best Practices" at the organization.
- End to end onboarding of new data visualization and dashboarding tools for Product Analytics domain (FalkonAI) from data mart and metrics design to dashboard development.

Sr. Decision Scientist - Pricing Analytics Team Lead - Remitly (Feb 2019-Oct 2021):

- Responsible for leading strategy on how exchange rates and fees are set for over 2000 international markets.
- Responsible for testing and retrospective analyses generating >\$4M in annualized incremental revenue. Conducted over 50 tests and retrospective analyses during tenure using Bayesian AB testing and Structural Time Series Models.

Technical Sales Engineer: Behavioral Neuroscience - Plexon, Inc (Sept 2015-Sept 2018):

- Global customer sales- Increased sales conversions of product lines by 20% and boosted sales of products by \$300,000.
- Product management Prioritized feature development, troubleshot, and tested video tracking software. Spearheaded development of new technology Multi-Fiber Photometry System.
- Technical support Support for video tracking, optogenetics, and high-throughput neurophysiology software.

Education:

PhD Psychology: Brain and Behaviour Concentration: University of Toronto

M.A. Experimental Psychology: Wake Forest University

B.S. Psychology (Summa Cum Laude): Appalachian State University, Minor: Mathematics